The on-request from this side of the room would be that should allow you to manage personnel
even tighter.
Yes.
Yeah.
Looks good.
Congratulations on your work.
Thank you.
Can I bring this up to date, right?
Yes.
So is there any issues with software or anything like that to run this system?
All of that is included in the final cost.
And they also include training with that as well.
And then we'll give us a card system that will allow us to tag everything quickly and
efficiently.
If they won't be.
And overnight think like I said, we have over 30,000 items in the library.
But it will allow us to scan it.
It will automatically pop out the label tag directly to that item and move on.
So we'll be able to pull the scan.
The tag is to get back up.
And go down the child.
So no more.
No more doing decimal system.
Everything will still be organized and everything the way that it is.
It will just allow us to not have to scan everything.
Sorry.
That's a poor 10th of June.
It was a successful day.
Last week.
So.
It's good to stop.
Thank you.
Was there an accident in there?
Yeah.
Did we have to vote on it?
I'll make a motion when I approve it.
I'll second.
These steps.
Hi.
So.
Thank you.
Hi.
10.
8th amendment to health care service and agreement between free and health.
System and the Mila.
Authorised City Manager.
Sign.
Mr. Cindy.
Thank you.
So basically this is just a housekeeping item.
Every year we have.
The prime and hospital that jump is part of our medical network for our employees.
We just have to update their.
The position fee schedule, which is something that is negotiated by our third party.
Ministry of.
We.
Uh.
So.
At this time, what they done in past me.
My.
He's had a different.
He's scheduled for all their different clients.
But they've provided this year.
So they'll all have the same.
He's scheduled.
Which is.
Same.
But we have to have.
Uh.
The signature.
He's.
Second.
Parker.
Hi.
Stoneburg.
David.
He's.
Thanks.
11.
21.
So, I hope you all had read the action decision request, but I want to touch on some of
those things, because the history of what we went through is important for this.
As you'll recall, the voters in 2018 legalized medical marijuana in the state of Oklahoma.
And licenses started getting issued 30 days after that was done.
It wasn't till over a year later in 2019, but the legislature passed legislation that
allowed municipalities to regulate medical marijuana businesses and their communities.
So by time we had the right to do that, we already had a bunch of businesses that were
in place.
And basically, under the law, they were grandfathered in, we were stuck with it.
We did pass that first ordinance in 2019, but in 2020, the council at that time made
it clear that they wanted to set aside the downtown district and try to not have medical
marijuana businesses there.
We already had a handful.
There were a few that were already operating, and so we were kind of stuck with those.
But at that time, they enacted an amendment to this ordinance that basically said there would
be no new medical marijuana businesses in the downtown area.
And downtown roughly is Steve Owens Boulevard to the railroad tracks from A Street to A Street.
So it's a six block area that we're talking about.
We authorized those businesses that were already in operation to continue in business.
If we hadn't done that, we would have been sued and we would have lost on that.
But we did put in provisions that if a business that's already there gets shut down, then they
can't reopen.
And so after the last meeting, the mayor of talk with me about that, and you wanted to make
sure that we had that as tight as we could for the downtown area.
That's all we're talking about is the downtown area.
As you all know, we've got marijuana businesses all over town for further operations.
And we did that ordinance in 2020.
There was kind of best guess as to what issues may come up.
Since then, we have had issues come up with one business in particular, and so we have a little bit more of a solid framework with which to assess our ordinance.
And so with that in mind, I went back in, made some amendments to the ordinance.
The red line copy that you all got, I think, first of all, reaffirms in doing this ordinance.
You all are reaffirming the decision that you don't want medical marijuana businesses in the downtown area to the extent that we don't have to.
And that if a business that is already there shuts down, then for whatever reason, they can't reopen.
And under the state statute that we have, it's my opinion that we're valid in doing what we're doing.
Basically, the ordinance says that we can regulate them through zoning.
The only thing we can't do is just prohibit any medical marijuana business from the city.
Well, obviously, we're not doing that, because we have mall over the city.
It's just that we don't want them in that particular area of the city.
And so, hence you have this ordinance in front of you.
And so doing, I just want to re-emphasize that you would be addressing the same thing that the council that was in place in 2020 did by saying,
You really don't want those businesses in the downtown area.
I point out that we had a lot of problems, particularly with the one business.
Lots of complaints from other businesses in the area.
Those have gone away to the best of my knowledge since the one has been shut down.
And this is intended to just strengthen our position.
If somebody were to challenge us on not allowing medical marijuana businesses in the downtown district.
And with that, I'd be glad to answer any questions.
I'll make a motion to approve, please.
Parker?
Aye.
E-SIP.
Davis?
Cerevine?
Aye.
Double Hi.
12.
The emergency call is oral order.
It's 2021-06, the MindExsection.
26-1441.
The amount of marijuana businesses and personal use droids.
Or what is the order that we just demanded?
Or putting an induction at correct例.
No, this.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Good.
David.
All right.
Good.
Hi.
13 staff reports, 14 mayor and council community announcements.
Everybody go to the parade.
Yeah.
It's good, right?
Wonderful.
It's great.
That couldn't have been on my own people.
So that way.
So I drove one of the floats in the parade.
And it's unbelievable.
I couldn't believe how many people were lying down to him.
My float brought.
And I've candy that we should have been able to do it twice.
We ran out in two blocks.
We ran out too.
I said, I'm not as both of you.
You have to need them throwing me in.
You're too late.
That's too far down.
The only negative I would say came away from it.
That the beginning was a little bit disorganized.
I mean, there's a lot of people else.
It's understandable because the whole street was blocked off.
Yeah.
That's some of the comments that I'd heard that is definitely something that we need to look at.
I know in the past they said they've done some things to try to rope people off or give them back, which, you know, even
streaming rope or whatever, probably not going to prevent people.
But we didn't have a lot of, we get children, but we also had some young adults who were going in and out of traffic, gathering candy and things.
Probably some adults.
Which probably is something that we should take a closer look at in the public safety aspect of having all the large vehicles coming through there.
We also had a vendor that I was not pleased with the way they were blocking traffic at times.
Floats were literally having to swore towards other sides of the street to go around this
vendor's cart, who was just stopping it in the basically the middle of the road while they were
selling their wares.
And although I don't know that we discourage them from doing that, I do think they should probably
follow some tighter guidelines.
Do we offer licenses for that?
Or is it just anyone who wants to come down?
I think there is a requirement.
I'm not mistaken.
There's an ordinance that requires somebody to have a license to sell on Main Street,
but I do not believe that these individuals were necessarily licensed, but that is
something that I've asked them out.
I feel like it should be licensed.
It feels like we should be able to confine them to the sidewalks and walking up and down
the sidewalks instead of intractive.
Well, personally, I didn't get very many complaints about that whole evening.
The only complaints I got were about the vendors.
They didn't like the fact that they were trying to be there with their family to enjoy the parade
and they kept trying to get pedal stuff and they didn't like it.
That was the complaints I got.
I don't remember those being there before, but I may be wrong.
I think they were there last year.
I do remember last year.
I've been there like four or five years, but it's been a long time.
I don't think we need them.
I think if they were available, I mean that may not be something we have a problem.
But having them going up and down the street in the street while the parade is trying to
travel may not be the best.
Or would designate a spot in downtown where they are at and people want to do that, we'll go to
them.
I think that would come across a lot better rather than I do too.
But anyway, my comment and the reason that I brought it out was just I was really amazed
at the outcome.
I was a little concerned with how tight it got in a couple of places with the kids being pushed
and driving a big truck and not being able to see.
But overall, it was fantastic turning out.
From the numbers I heard and including even the numbers tonight, I think they were close to
the 25 to 30 more floats than our largest, our previous largest parade.
I know the Tulsa parade was this last weekend.
They had 60 some entries.
And we had 80 some, which is pretty impressive.
It was impressive.
And it felt more spread out to you, but the Tulsa parade was that you know for this area picture
was one of the biggest praise that I attended that weekend and I did four of them with my
little boat and that boat was little, I don't think it was that little, I just looked
that little.
And my little hat.
He was waving his tassel around, he was crying out.
He was crying out.
The parade was good.
I'd like to see, you know, we did the tree lighting.
I don't know if that's been done before I assume it has, because we had the magic button.
But it was good.
And I think next year, we probably, you know, invite some of the churches at a time.
We do not have much time this time.
And we're kids.
Every church had a float.
And back when we were kids, they were actually floats and not just pick up to pull in trailers.
Right.
So I would actually see that go again.
Yeah, back when I drove your school bus.
She can work on napkins.
Yeah.
Anyway, that's all you guys.
I just wanted to have some conversation around there.
Because I talked to the green.
I'll just put the most part.
I'm the green.
Really?
Yeah.
Down the tree.
We agree.
Yeah.
You could actually steal here.
Pretty good.
Perhaps you had to get up on.
Yeah.
Well, I think we coordinate something next year.
And we have some bleachers.
Is there a committee that's in charge of that?
Of what?
That's great.
I don't know that for that.
It's a shame.
Chamber is.
Greg and they had meetings that plan for all this before.
Maybe we should recommend that they should have a planning meeting.
A head time?
Maybe.
I don't know.
December 1st.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean, anything's better than nothing.
It's all on that day, maybe they could discuss the business,
but while they're at it.
Yes.
Maybe even like November 1st.
I don't know.
I'm just thinking.
There was a few things that seemed like maybe they were a little bit.
Disorganized.
It could have been better if they were planned.
Just don't know.
But I think, too, if we get some stuff out there and encourage some of the churches to get a floating in that that you used to.
Even if it's sort of youth group or something that puts one together.
Encourage our businesses to decorate downtown.
And maybe have a contest for businesses downtown to decorate.
I think it'd be.
We could really live it up down in a little bit.
So.
We could give away chamberbox for the winners.
We could give away chamberbox.
In January.
Wow.
Anyone else?
No.
You're only talking about an update.
There's this.
This.
as the oral arguments. So the Council last Thursday, I said all of you an email link. If you had
an opportunity to listen to that, that was the actual oral arguments for the appeal that my
Emma has. A lot of the work that has been done by the attorneys given the invoice that you all
occurred earlier. But the oral arguments were actually heard last Thursday morning in DC by the
Court of Appeals, U.S. Court of Appeals. And you know, the best you can say for many
things like those oral arguments, which there was no judgment or anything ruled or in that
time of course, because that was just an opportunity for the judges to ask questions and
get answers, and then they will be evaluating mostly the written content or what they were provided,
and then they will be ruling, you know, the best guess from what attorneys tell us could be as
early as early February. He could be as late as June before there is a ruling on this. Of course,
the appeal is related to the fact that FERC kicked the can down the road, if you will, on a ruling,
where the city felt that GRDA had not appelled the current license as in place. You know, we talk a lot
about relicensing. Well, there's a current license that's in place today and has certain obligations
that are placed on. GRDA in one of those obligations is the purchase of any land in the
easements of the flowage of land that floods. And so that has been our appeal is that FERC should go ahead
and make a decision on whether or not GRDA should hold their current license or uphold their current
license and purchase that land. FERC had at the time kicked the can down the road and said they
would address it during relicensing. So the city filed a appeal and that's the appeal that was heard
in the New York argument last Thursday. I would say that there were positive aspects to the oral arguments.
There were several things that were brought to light that were, I would say in the city's favor that
there were three judges and several of the or at least two of the judges seem to have a lot of knowledge
based on the reports that we had filed with them. Obviously they had read those reports because they
were very knowledgeable of things we had actually put in reports. So that being said that's always a positive
thing to know that they've studied it and I think they were genuinely concerned about the citizens of
my and my based on some of the comments they made during the oral arguments.
I would certainly encourage anybody to go listen to it, it's all in line as you know, the U.S.
Court of Appeals is online and has a YouTube channel, so you can find it listen to it.
The audio was not good, it was extremely difficult to understand.
Certain people in the room, you could hear occasionally, but everybody else, it was kind of a struggle.
And that was, I guess because they were not well-prepared to do this with just audio broadcast.
So they were kind of winging it, and you could tell.
But other than that, we will certainly report on anything that comes out of that oral arguments
as we learn anything new.
And again, I think there will be continued discussion with the council on the city doing some
type of formal report to citizens and maybe January or February that we bring all of the information
that we have and have a conversation in a public forum, distancing the entire history of the legal disputes
that myma has had because of flooding.
We can talk about what we're doing with the silver jackets in preparation for potential
future flooding.
We can talk about the appeal, we can talk about the real licensing, we can talk about the legal challenges,
we can talk about the cost of the legal challenges and what the city has faced to date and
any cost that we might see in the future.
All of those things, each of you as council members has discussed the fact that you think
this is something that the citizens of myma should be fully versed on and understand so that
they can help support the indoor and make a decision or help the council make decisions on how
we move forward as a community.
So that being said, anything else you want me to add?
Mr. Mayor, I'm happy to.
Do you have a little bit of an answer to any questions?
Well, I'm not.
I listen as well and there was some positive stuff buying out of this, I was pleasantly
surprised.
Yes, it was I.
It's always encouraging when the individuals that we rely on to make decisions of this magnitude
obviously take the time to educate themselves, which we would say in the citizens of myma that
is good for us when the decisions make such as the judges and the court of appeals educate
themselves to all of the facts, I think that's in our favor, so that was good to see.
Did I make it?
They were done, Bob?
Yeah.
16 this meeting would not be continued from the Calce Travers
and we could be in the staff rooms for the purpose of the executive session.
I don't care.
And I respect your decision.
Good job, Michael.
What's your name?
That's a 15-yard.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, one job.
I'm going to the election to the adjourn.
Just to let us.
Okay.
What'd you get up here?
The fire is out of the executive session.
I'm back into the regular session.
This is the Monastery Council.
And we'll lose the night team, action item.
Both on the international association fire fires.
Local night team 69.
First of all, here are 21-22 contract.
So moved.
Second.
E-step.
All right.
Davis.
Under.
Upstate.
Parker.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
To all of you guys.
We appreciate their service.
Thank you, guys.
And 20.
Second.
Davis.
So full.
Hi.
Denver.
Parker.
Hi.